The Homesman is a western, drama film directed by Tommy Lee Jones.
When three women living on the edge of the American frontier are driven mad by harsh pioneer
life, the task of saving them falls to the pious, independent-minded Mary Bee Cuddy.
Transporting the women by covered wagon to Iowa, she soon realizes just how daunting the
journey will be, and employs a low-life drifter, George Briggs, to join her.
The unlikely pair and the three women head east, where a waiting
minister and his wife have offered to take the women in.
But the group first must traverse the harsh Nebraska Territories marked
by stark beauty, psychological peril and constant threat.
Mary Bee Cuddy, played by Hilary Swank.
George Briggs, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Arabella Sours, played by Grace Gummer.
Theoline Belknap, played by Miranda Otto.
Gro Svendsen, played by Sonja Richter.
The Freighter, played by Tim Blake Nelson.
The Homesman is a 2014 Western historical drama film set in the 1850s Midwest and directed by Tommy Lee Jones and
written by Jones, Kieran Fitzgerald, and Wesley Oliver based on the 1988 novel by Glendon Swarthout.
The film stars Jones and Hilary Swank and also features Meryl Streep, Grace Gummer,
Miranda Otto, Hailee Steinfeld, John Lithgow, Jesse Plemons, and James Spader.
The Homesman competed for the Palme d'Or in the main competition section at the 2014 Cannes Film Festival
and got a North American limited release on November 14, 2014, by Roadside Attractions.
The Homesman has received mostly positive reviews from critics.
Rotten Tomatoes gave the film a rating of 81%.
The title refers to the task of taking immigrants back
home, which was typically a man's job.
The film explores themes of dancing, based on novel or
book, native american, revenge, wild west.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.